<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
        "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<article>

    <articleinfo>
        <author><firstname>Wikipedia Contributors</firstname></author>
        <title>Iron Gods</title>
    </articleinfo>

    <para>

        Ashok Banker's next book immediately following the Ramayana is
        said to be a novel tentatively titled "Iron Gods" scheduled to
        be published in 2007. A contemporary novel, it is an epic hard
        science fiction story about a war between the gods of
        different faiths.  Weary of the constant infighting between
        religious sects and their deities, God (aka Allah, Yahweh,
        brahman, or whatever one chooses to call the Supreme Deity)
        wishes to destroy creation altogether.

    </para>

    <para>

        A representation of prophets and holy warriors led by Ganesa,
        the elephant-headed Hindu deity, randomly picks a sample of
        mortals, five of whom are the main protagonists of the
        book--an American Catholic, an Indian Hindu, a Pakistani
        Muslim, a Japanese Buddhist, and a Japanese Shinto follower.
        The mortal sampling, called a 'Palimpsest' is ferried aboard a
        vast Dyson's Sphere artifact termed The Jewel, which is built
        around the sun itself, contains retransplanted cities and
        landscapes brought from multiple parallel Earths and is the
        size of 12,000 Earths.  It is also a spaceship travelling to
        the end of creation, where the Palimpsest is to present itself
        before God to plead clemency for all creation.

    </para>

    <para>

        Meanwhile, it is upto the five protagonists, aided by Ganesa
        and a few concerned individuals, including Lucifer
        Morningstar, Ali Abu Tarab, King David and his son Solomon,
        and others, to bring about peace among the myriad warring
        faiths. The question is whether or not they can do so before
        the audience with God, and if they can do so peacefully--for
        pressure is mounting to wage one final War of Wars to end all
        war itself.

    </para>

    <sidebar>
        <para>

            (Excerpt taken from
            http://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Ashok_Banker&amp;oldid=86219280
            under the GNU Free Documentation License)

        </para>
    </sidebar>

</article>
